VICTOR SCHOLZ

(407) 353-5174 | vgscholz@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY | Portfolio | Github | Medium | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Driven software developer with experience building full stack applications with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. A background in the service industry combines a proficiency in collaboration and team empowerment with a passion for problem solving.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Postgres, SQL, PostGis, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), React, Three.js, Cannon.js, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Aeropress Dice - Demo | Github

3D Physics based application inspired by the Aeropress dice that allows the user to roll the dice and save recipes.

- Created in React with the React-Three-Fiber and Use-Cannon libraries in conjunction with a Rails back-end.
- Randomized the set velocity, rotation, and position for each dice so that no roll was the same.
- Rendered the results of each roll on the plane while utilizing React Hooks to manage state.

District Build NYC - Demo | Github

An interactive map of NYC that allows the user to click on any of the 37,000 historical buildings and see it's information.

- Developed React/Mapbox front-end and Rails/Active Record/PostGis back-end application.
- Seeded database with a GeoJSON file from NYC Open Data and loaded that information into the map as a clickable layer.

Churn - Github

An application that keeps track of credit cards currently available along with their associated fees and categories.

- Communicated with the CCstack RESTful API endpoint to render credit card information through Rails back-end.
- Engineered user interface using JavaScript and improved user experience with responsive design techniques.

EXPERIENCE

THE ESPRESSO SPECIALIST

Brooklyn, NY

Service Manager

Sept. 2019 – July 2020

- Coordinated all scheduling of service and operation of coffee equipment for 3,000 accounts in New York City.
- Handled all invoicing for repair and install work that averaged \$36,000 per week across three technicians.

THE GLASS KNIFE

Winter Park, FL

Beverage Program Director

July 2018 - June 2019

- Oversaw hiring of the six-person beverage team as well as the drink menu creation.
- Became Onyx Coffee Lab's highest grossing wholesale account with over \$110,000 spent on coffee in a one year period.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming bootcamp

July 2020 - Oct. 2020

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY - COLLEGE OF SOCIAL SCIENCES

Bachelor of Science, Interdisciplinary Social Sciences

Concentrations in Social Entrepreneurship and Economics

Tallahassee, FL Sept. 2014 – June 2018